Guide to the Sylvère Lotringer Papers and Semiotext(e) Archive, 1960-2004 (Bulk 1973-2000) MSS.221
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series V: Sylvere Lotringer Projects, 174642
  - Subseries A: Writing, 174644
    - "I Talked about God with Antonin Artaud" resources - correspondence with Dr. Latremoliere, info on electroshock, c. 1985; 196649 (Box 45, Folder 28)
    - "Ici New York", 1980's; 196650 (Box 45, Folder 29)
    - Impulse - Death Issue, Undated; 196651 (Box 45, Folder 30)
    - Impulse - Death Issue - Interview with James van der Zee, Undated; 196652 (Box 45, Folder 31)
    - Interview by Rainer Ganahl, c. 1997; 196653 (Box 45, Folder 32)
    - "Jacques Lacan: Le pur sujet des signifiant" (unpublished), 1973-1974; 196654 (Box 45, Folder 33)
    - "James van der Zee on my Mind", Undated; 196655 (Box 45, Folder 34)
    - "Leçon de textes" (on Claud Simon) 1 of 2, undated; 196690 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - "Leçon de textes" (on Claud Simon) 2 of 2, undated; 196691 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - for Les Lettres françaises - correspondence only (includes letters from John Irving, Philip Roth, Bernard Malamud), 1960s; 196692 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - for Les Lettres françaises - Virginia Woolf photos, circa 1962; 196713 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - for Les Lettres françaises - Virginia Woolf photos, circa 1962; 196714 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - "Les liasons dangereuses" (a play), circa 1970; 196715 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - "Lies" (Catalogue essay on Carol Irving), 1994; 196716 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - "Lisible et scriptible" (on Edith Wharton), undated; 196717 (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - "Listen to Me" see also "Lost Sol", undated; 196718 (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - "La Lit et la Lettre" (on Sade), undated; 196719 (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - "Literature and Evil", undated; 196720 (Box 46, Folder 11)
    - "Lost Sol" see also "Listen to Me" and "The Miracle of Lascaux", 1988; 196721 (Box 46, Folder 12)
    - "Mme Bovary", 2002; 196722 (Box 46, Folder 13)
    - "The man who slips" (for Rainer Ganahl catalog), circa 2005; 196723 (Box 46, Folder 14)
    - "The man who slips" (Berlin draft), circa 2005; 196724 (Box 46, Folder 15)
    - "Michael, Funeral Director", circa 1982; 196725 (Box 46, Folder 16)
    - "The Miracle of Lascaux" see also "Lost Sol", undated; 196726 (Box 46, Folder 17)
    - "Les Misérables" (Bataille après tout, long version), circa 1995; 196727 (Box 46, Folder 18)
    - "Les Miserables" alternate title "Les Malheureux", circa 1995; 196728 (Box 46, Folder 19)
    - "Les Miserablès" (on Bataille), circa 1995; 196729 (Box 46, Folder 20)
    - "Les Miserablès" - English version, circa 1995; 196730 (Box 46, Folder 21)
    - "Motel-suicide", undated; 196731 (Box 46, Folder 22)
    - "Muller-Cocktail" (includes correspondence), circa 1988; 196732 (Box 46, Folder 23)
    - "Mutants", undated; 196733 (Box 46, Folder 24)
    - "New York Interviews" - Intro "Confessions d'un ventriloque", circa 1983; 196734 (Box 46, Folder 25)
    - "New York Interviews" - Intro "Confessions d'un ventriloque", undated; 196886 (Box 46, Folder 26)
    - "New York Interviews" draft of "Confessions d'un ventriloque" with interview transcripts, correspondence, undated; 196887 (Box 46, Folder 27)
    - "New York Interviews" draft of "Confessions d'un ventriloque" with interviews transcripts, undated; 196888 (Box 46, Folder 28)
    - "New York Interviews" - copies and galleys, undated; 196889 (Box 46, Folder 29)
    - "New York Interviews" - outline and copies, undated; 196890 (Box 46, Folder 30)
    - "New York Interviews" - complete set, undated; 196891 (Box 46, Folder 31)
    - "New York Interviews" - copies, undated; 196892 (Box 46, Folder 32)
    - "New York Interviews" - press for German publication as "New Yorker Gespräche", 1983; 196893 (Box 46, Folder 33)
    - "No comment" (on Felix Guattari), undated; 196894 (Box 46, Folder 34)
    - "An open letter to Susan Sontag", undated; 196895 (Box 46, Folder 35)
    - "Oublier Artaud" Lotringer/Baudrillard "Moma" dialogue at Drawing Centre, undated; 196896 (Box 46, Folder 36)
    - Overexposed - correspondence, circa 1988; 196897 (Box 46, Folder 37)
    - Overexposed - Dr. Stoller correspondence, confidentiality, 1988; 196898 (Box 46, Folder 38)
    - Overexposed - legal problems, undated; 196899 (Box 46, Folder 39)
    - Overexposed - Dr. Abel interviews, complete set of transcripts, undated; 196900 (Box 46, Folder 40)
    - Overexposed - Bob Stein transcript, undated; 196901 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Overexposed - interview transcripts "cut-ups", undated; 196902 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Overexposed - "Copy Tape #3", undated; 196903 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Overexposed - Intro, undated; 196904 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Overexposed - Intro, Undated; 196953 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Overexposed - Intro II, Undated; 196954 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Overexposed - Intro, Last version, Undated; 196955 (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Overexposed - "Sex - chapter 2", Undated; 196956 (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Overexposed - "Sex Clinic" (1 of 2), Undated; 196957 (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - Overexposed - "Sex Clinic" (2 of 2), Undated; 196958 (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - Overexposed - "Chapter 3 - Enjoy / Masturbatory Sessions", Undated; 196959 (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - Overexposed - Conclusion, Undated; 196960 (Box 47, Folder 12)
    - Overexposed - "Conclusion: Double Talk", Undated; 196961 (Box 47, Folder 13)
    - Overexposed, Undated; 196962 (Box 47, Folder 14)
    - Overexposed, Undated; 196963 (Box 47, Folder 15)
    - Overexposed - Setting manuscript (1 of 2), Undated; 196964 (Box 47, Folder 16)
    - Overexposed - Setting manuscript (2 of 2), Undated; 196965 (Box 47, Folder 17)
    - Overexposed - Drafts and Resources, Undated; 196966 (Box 47, Folder 18)
    - Overexposed - Sex Clinic consent forms, French draft, Undated; 196967 (Box 47, Folder 19)
    - Overexposed - Resources, Undated; 196968 (Box 47, Folder 20)
    - Overexposed - Resources - "Sex offenses: Penal Law, Criminal Procedure Law", Undated; 196969 (Box 47, Folder 21)
    - Overexposed - Resources, photocopies of duty statements (BDSM, incest, pedo, rape), Undated; 196970 (Box 47, Folder 22)
    - Overexposed - Resources on sex offenders, Undated; 196971 (Box 47, Folder 23)
    - Overexposed - Resources - Sex cards, Undated; 196972 (Box 47, Folder 24)
    - Overexposed - Resources - Abel's "Itentifying dangerous child molesters", Undated; 196973 (Box 47, Folder 25)
    - Overexposed - Resources - "Characteristics of Adolescent Incest Perpetrators", Undated; 196974 (Box 47, Folder 26)
    - Overexposed - ads, Undated; 196975 (Box 47, Folder 27)
    - Overexposed - cover and blurbs, Undated; 196976 (Box 47, Folder 28)
    - Overexposed - Publication information, Undated; 196977 (Box 47, Folder 29)
    - Overexposed - book launch flyers, Undated; 196978 (Box 47, Folder 30)
    - Overexposed - Press and promo correspondence, c. 1989; 196979 (Box 47, Folder 31)
    - Overexposed - Press and reactions, Undated; 196980 (Box 47, Folder 32)
    - Overexposed - file, press, Undated; 196981 (Box 47, Folder 33)
    - Overexposed - reviews, Undated; 196982 (Box 47, Folder 34)
    - Overexposed - contract for French publication, Undated; 196983 (Box 47, Folder 35)
    - Overexposed - "Surexposé" - French translation, Undated; 196984 (Box 47, Folder 36)
    - Overexposed - press and ongoing research on Dr. Abel, Undated; 196985 (Box 47, Folder 37)
    - "Parole textamentaire", Undated; 196987 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - "Parole textamentaire" alt title "Le nouveau textament", Undated; 196988 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - "Parole textamentaire" - notes, Undated; 196989 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - "Peraldi", c. 2007; 196990 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - "Le philosophe et son double" and Artaud texts, Undated; 196991 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - "Playing with Fire" pm Artaud and Bataille, Undated; 196992 (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - "Police Sexualities", Undated; 196993 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - "La politique des Restes" (Semio 1), c. 1974; 196994 (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - "La politique des Restes:, 1974; 196995 (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - "Pour une sémiotique materialiste", 1974; 196996 (Box 48, Folder 10)
    - Preston, John - interview and other S&M writings, Undated; 196997 (Box 48, Folder 11)
    - "La Quete du Graal" - fragment, Undated; 196998 (Box 48, Folder 12)
    - "Quiet day in Ivri" (on Artaud), 1990; 196999 (Box 48, Folder 13)
    - "Quiet Days in Ivri", Undated; 197000 (Box 48, Folder 14)
    - "Retour d'Apoétique", Undated; 197001 (Box 48, Folder 15)
    - "Sacher-Masoch, l'humour et l'ironie" and introduction to "Venus in Furs", Undated; 197002 (Box 48, Folder 16)
    - "Le Salut par les Juifs: De Bloy à Céline", Undated; 197003 (Box 48, Folder 17)
    - "Savage Mind" lecture on Artaud at NYU, 1996; 197004 (Box 48, Folder 18)
    - "Savoir Créer", Undated; 197005 (Box 48, Folder 19)
    - "Sex in Necropolis", Undated; 197006 (Box 48, Folder 20)
    - "Shell-Shocked" for Shock '88 conference, 1988; 197007 (Box 48, Folder 21)
    - "Shooting Death" - Book proposal, Undated; 197010 (Box 48, Folder 22)
    - "Shooting Death" - Correspondence, John Jost on Nick's Movie, Undated; 197011 (Box 48, Folder 23)
    - "Shooting Death" - Connie Bessis interview, Undated; 197012 (Box 48, Folder 24)
    - "Shooting Death" - Pierre Cottell interview transcript, Undated; 197013 (Box 48, Folder 25)
    - "Shooting Death" - Jean Evans interview, Undated; 197014 (Box 48, Folder 26)
    - "Shooting Death" - Tom Farrell interview transcript, 1982; 197015 (Box 48, Folder 27)
    - "Shooting Death" - Laurie Frank interview transcript, 1982; 197016 (Box 48, Folder 28)
    - "Shooting Death" - John Houseman interview transcript, Undated; 197017 (Box 48, Folder 29)
    - "Shooting Death" - Betty and Tim Ray interview transcripts, 1983-1986; 197018 (Box 48, Folder 30)
    - "Shooting Death" - Julie Ray interview transcript, 1983; 197019 (Box 48, Folder 31)
    - "Shooting Death" - Susan Ray interview transcript, undated; 197045 (Box 48, Folder 32)
    - "Shooting Death" - various interview transcripts, 1983; 197046 (Box 48, Folder 33)
    - "Shooting Death" - Intro, undated; 197047 (Box 48, Folder 34)
    - "Shooting Death" - manuscript, undated; 197048 (Box 48, Folder 35)
    - "Shooting Death" - manuscript, undated; 197049 (Box 48, Folder 36)
    - "Shooting Death" - manuscript and original text "La Morte en direct" for Andere Sinema, circa 1991; 197050 (Box 48, Folder 37)
    - "Shooting Death" - manuscript, undated; 197109 (Box 48, Folder 38)
    - "Shooting Death" - notes, circa 1982; 197110 (Box 48, Folder 39)
    - "Shooting Death" - notes on Nick's movie, undated; 197111 (Box 48, Folder 40)
    - "Shooting Death" - notes and release forms, undated; 197112 (Box 48, Folder 41)
    - "Shooting Death" - translation and original "Les politiques de la fin", undated; 197113 (Box 48, Folder 42)
    - "Shooting Death" - "Nick Ray at NYU", undated; 197114 (Box 48, Folder 43)
    - "Shooting Death" - References Nick Rays' "Bill W. Story" screenplay, undated; 197115 (Box 48, Folder 44)
    - "Shooting Death" - resources - script "The Bill W. Story" by Andy Lewis and Nick Ray [labelled by S.L. as "Artaud Script", undated; 197116 (Box 48, Folder 45)
    - "Shooting Death" - references - Wenders/Ray "Lightening Over Water" 1 of 2, 1985; 197117 (Box 48, Folder 46)
    - "Shooting Death" - references - Wenders/Ray "Lightening Over Water" 2 of 2, 1985; 197118 (Box 48, Folder 47)
    - "Shooting Death" - References - "Lightening Over Water" press and clippings, undated; 197119 (Box 48, Folder 48)
    - "Shooting Death" - references - Wim Wenders' "Wings of Desire" screenplay, undated; 197120 (Box 48, Folder 49)
    - "Structure et histoire" including correspondence with F. Wahl, c. 1970; 197121 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - "The Sufferer Artist" on Artaud, Undated; 197122 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - "Suffering Bodies" on Artaud, Undated; 197123 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - "Superstructure et psychologie" on Bataille - unpublished, Undated; 197124 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - "Théorie du Roman" outline and grant application, 1974-1982; 197125 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - "Théorie du Roman" - "Les deix styles de la representation", Undated; 197126 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - "Théorie du Roman" - "Erec et Enée: Le roman épique", Undated; 197127 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - "Théorie du Roman" - "Erec et Enée", Undated; 197128 (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - "Théorie du Roman" - "Manon L'Echo", Undated; 197129 (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - "Théorie du Roman" - "Manon L'Echo", Undated; 197130 (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - "Théorie du Roman" - "Mesure de la démesure", Undated; 197131 (Box 49, Folder 11)
    - "Théorie du Roman" - "Proust Polymorphe", Undated; 197132 (Box 49, Folder 12)
    - "Théorie du Roman" - "Une revolution remanesque", Undated; 197133 (Box 49, Folder 13)
    - "Théorie du Roman" - "Roman et différence" and correspondence, Undated; 197134 (Box 49, Folder 14)
    - "Théorie du Roman" - "Sade Insecticide", Undated; 197135 (Box 49, Folder 15)
    - "Théorie du Roman" - "Vice de Forme", Undated; 197136 (Box 49, Folder 16)
    - "Théorie du Roman" - Untitled - on Robbe-Grillet, Undated; 197137 (Box 49, Folder 17)
    - "Théorie du Roman", Undated; 197138 (Box 49, Folder 18)
    - "The Third Wave NY Art 1982-3", Undated; 197139 (Box 49, Folder 19)
    - "The Third Wave: Art Theory", Undated; 197140 (Box 49, Folder 20)
    - "Virginia Woolf and Death" (unpublished), Undated; 197141 (Box 49, Folder 21)
    - "Voice", 1986; 197142 (Box 49, Folder 22)
    - "Voyage to Rodez", Undated; 197143 (Box 49, Folder 23)
    - "The Will to Madness" - Essay for Artaud critical anthology, Undated; 197144 (Box 49, Folder 24)
    - Unknown Title (Catalogue essay on the Chapman Brothers), Undated; 197145 (Box 49, Folder 25)
    - "Unknown Title" - material for unknown performance piece, Undated; 197146 (Box 49, Folder 26)
    - Untitled poems, Undated; 197147 (Box 49, Folder 27)
    - Untitled poem / song, Undated; 197148 (Box 49, Folder 28)
    - Various short texts foldered together, Undated; 197149 (Box 49, Folder 29)
  - Subseries B: Film, 174645
    Materials are arranged alphabetically by film title and include scripts, notes, shooting schedules, promotional materials, etc.
    - Film School - Columbia Classes, c. 1986-1987; 197150 (Box 49, Folder 30)
    - Film School - Course Materials (misc.), c. 1983; 197151 (Box 49, Folder 31)
    - Film School - Directing I (Larry Engel), 1983-1984; 197152 (Box 49, Folder 32)
    - Film School - Photocopied articles, Undated; 197153 (Box 49, Folder 33)
    - Film School - Photocopied articles, Undated; 197154 (Box 49, Folder 34)
    - Film School - Photocopied articles, Undated; 197155 (Box 49, Folder 35)
    - Film School - "Scriptwriting" notebook, 1983; 197179 (Box 49, Folder 36)
    - Film School - Sharff Class, c. 1984; 197180 (Box 49, Folder 37)
    - "Foolproof Illusion" logging for final version, 1987; 197181 (Box 49, Folder 38)
    - "Foolproof Illusions" notes, Undated; 197182 (Box 49, Folder 39)
    - "Foolproof Illusion" script, Undated; 197183 (Box 49, Folder 40)
    - "Foolproof Illusion" source material; "Transcript of performances on Artaud by Susan Cooper, Penny Arcade, David Rattray for Foolproof Illusions", 1985; 197184 (Box 49, Folder 41)
    - "How to Shoot a Crime" flyer, Undated; 197185 (Box 49, Folder 42)
    - "How to Shoot a Crime" interview with Terrence Sellers and others, c. 1984; 197186 (Box 49, Folder 43)
    - "How to Shoot a Crime" interview with Terrence Sellers and others, c. 1984; 197187 (Box 49, Folder 44)
    - "How to Shoot a Crime" photocopies of photographs, Undated; 197188 (Box 49, Folder 45)
    - "How to Shoot a Crime" press release, 1987; 197189 (Box 49, Folder 46)
    - "How to Shoot a Crime" research, Undated; 197190 (Box 49, Folder 47)
    - "How to Shoot a Crime" script, Undated; 197191 (Box 49, Folder 48)
    - "How to Shoot a Crime" script, Undated; 197192 (Box 49, Folder 49)
    - "How to Shoot a Crime" script, 1987; 197193 (Box 49, Folder 50)
    - "How to Shoot a Crime" text, Undated; 197194 (Box 49, Folder 51)
    - "How to Shoot a Crime" text, Undated; 197195 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - "How to Shoot a Crime" voice over text, Undated; 197196 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - "How to Shoot a Crime" voice over text and other notes, Undated; 197197 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - "How to Shoot a Crime" transcript / rough cut, Undated; 197198 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - "Second Hand Hitler" script, 1982-1983; 197199 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - "Too Sensitive to Touch", c. 1981; 197200 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - "Voyage to Rodez" negatives (with C.K.), Undated; 197201 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Subseries C: Conferences, Events and Tours, 181959
    Contains materials pertaining to conferences and events that Sylvere Lotringer participated in or organized outside the activities of the Semiotext(e) group. Also includes materials pertaining to lecture tours, and research trips. Materials are arranged alphabetically by conference, event or tour name.
    - Artaud Colloque (UQAM Montreal), 1993; 197202 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Artaud Events: Drawing Centre, MOMA, Anthology Film Archives, c. 1996; 197203 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - "Artaud Intime" Franklin Furnace, c. 1986; 197204 (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - "Artaud Intime" tour correspondence, 1986; 197205 (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - "Artaud Symposium" Drawing Centre, 1997; 197206 (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - Austrian Tour (Graz) on Semiotext(e), 1993; 197207 (Box 50, Folder 13)
    - Austria Tour Flyers, 1992; 197208 (Box 50, Folder 14)
    - Banff Centre for the Arts (Canada), 1994; 197209 (Box 50, Folder 15)
    - Banff Centre for the Arts (Canada), c. 1996; 197210 (Box 50, Folder 16)
    - Bataílle Apres tout (Orléans), 1993; 197211 (Box 50, Folder 17)
    - Bataille Apres tout (Orléans), 1993; 197212 (Box 50, Folder 18)
    - Cal Arts - Mellon Fellowship, 1991; 197213 (Box 50, Folder 19)
    - Cal Arts, 1994; 197214 (Box 50, Folder 20)
    - California Lecture Tour - Freud, Proust, Robbe-Grillet, c. 1976; 197215 (Box 50, Folder 21)
    - Celine: His American Presence (Duke), 1992; 197216 (Box 50, Folder 22)
    - Cioran Lecture (La Maison Français, NYU), 2005; 197217 (Box 50, Folder 23)
    - Columbia University Lecture, 1980; 197218 (Box 50, Folder 24)
    - Culture Talks - Lecture on Müller, Undated; 197219 (Box 50, Folder 25)
    - Deutscher Akademischer Austauschdienst (DAAD), c. 1985; 197220 (Box 50, Folder 26)
    - Deutscher Akademischer Austauschdienst (DAAD), c. 1990; 197221 (Box 50, Folder 27)
    - Delirrous Anthropology (NYU) Lecture on Artaud, 1996; 197222 (Box 50, Folder 28)
    - "Effets spéciaux" (Centre Pompidon), 2000-2001; 197223 (Box 50, Folder 29)
    - The End of the World (NYU - Columbia), 1986; 197224 (Box 50, Folder 30)
    - Richard Foreman panel, 1997; 197225 (Box 50, Folder 31)
    - "The French in New York during World War II" (Columbia), 1991; 197255 (Box 50, Folder 32)
    - French Theory (Columbia?), undated; 197256 (Box 50, Folder 33)
    - "French Theory in America" NYU, Drawing Centre, Guggenheim 1 of 2, 1997; 197257 (Box 50, Folder 34)
    - "French Theory in American" 2 of 2, 1997; 197258 (Box 50, Folder 35)
    - "French Theory in America", circa 1997; 197259 (Box 50, Folder 36)
    - Future Perfect / Present Tense (La Jolla Museum, San Diego), 1990; 197260 (Box 50, Folder 37)
    - Harvard research trip on Simone Weil, circa 1999; 197261 (Box 50, Folder 38)
    - (In)visible Cities (Columbia), circa 1999; 197262 (Box 50, Folder 39)
    - Kafka Colloque (Japan) 1 of 2, 1989; 197263 (Box 50, Folder 40)
    - Kafka Colloque (Japan) 2 of 2, 1989; 197264 (Box 50, Folder 41)
    - Lecture Schedule, 1993; 197265 (Box 50, Folder 42)
    - The Listening Room (Australian Radio Program) with Virilio, 1989; 197266 (Box 50, Folder 43)
    - Modern Communication and the Disappearance of Art and Politica (University of Montana) on Baudriallard, 1989; 197267 (Box 50, Folder 44)
    - New York Habitat, undated; 197268 (Box 50, Folder 45)
    - "New York Nowhere" in Graz, 1992; 197269 (Box 50, Folder 46)
    - "Post-modern summit" (BAM), circa 1986; 197270 (Box 50, Folder 47)
    - "Post-modern summit" (BAM), circa 1986; 197271 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - "Post-modern summit" (BAM), 1986; 197272 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - "Post-modern summit" (BAM), 1986; 197273 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - The Quiet in the Land (Maine), 1996; 197274 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Simone Weil in America (Columbia), 1999; 197275 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Simone Weil in America (Columbia), 1999; 197276 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Simone Weil in America (Columbia), 1999; 197277 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Simone Weil in America (Columbia), 1999; 197278 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - Socialist Scholars Conference (CUNY), circa 1985; 197279 (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - Theory and Practice of the Avant-Garde, undated; 197280 (Box 51, Folder 10)
    - US Lecture Tour, 1977; 197281 (Box 51, Folder 11)
    - Voices (UK tv program), 1983; 197282 (Box 51, Folder 12)
    - Voyages and Beaches - Discovery and the Pacific (New Zealand) lecture on Gaugain and Segalen, 1993; 197283 (Box 51, Folder 13)
    - WBAI interview on semiotics between Sylvere Lotringer and Etan Ben-Ami, 1982; 197284 (Box 51, Folder 14)
    - Whitney Independent Studies, 1996; 197285 (Box 51, Folder 15)
      Item inaccessible to researchers due to preservation treatment.
  - Subseries D: Academic Work, 181960
    Contains course materials, student bibliographies, and information on Sylvere's career at specific academic institutions. Materials are arranged alphabetically by folder name.
    - Art Center College of Design Faculty Performance Review, 1996; 197287 (Box 51, Folder 16)
    - Cal Arts, undated; 197288 (Box 51, Folder 17)
    - Case Western - Tours, 1971; 197289 (Box 51, Folder 18)
    - Case Western - misc, undated; 197290 (Box 51, Folder 19)
    - Case Western - Vidry, 1971; 197291 (Box 51, Folder 20)
    - Columbia Course evaluations, 1990; 197488 (Box 51, Folder 21)
    - Columbia - Department of French self-study report, 1997; 197489 (Box 51, Folder 22)
    - Columbia Newsletters and other Sylvere Lotringer mentions, Undated; 197490 (Box 51, Folder 23)
    - Columbia - Reid Hall program, 1973; 197491 (Box 51, Folder 24)
    - Columbia - Reid Hall French program budget, 1973; 197492 (Box 51, Folder 25)
    - Columbia - Reid Hall program, 1973; 197493 (Box 51, Folder 26)
    - Columbia - Reserve lists, 1972-1973; 197494 (Box 51, Folder 27)
    - Columbia - Salary and leaves, Undated; 197495 (Box 51, Folder 28)
    - Columbia - Miscellaneous, Undated; 197496 (Box 51, Folder 29)
    - "Antonin Artaud" course materials, Undated; 197497 (Box 51, Folder 30)
    - "Baudelaire / Mallarme" syllabus, 2003; 197498 (Box 51, Folder 31)
    - "Beyond Post-structuralism" course materials, 1993; 197499 (Box 51, Folder 32)
    - "Burroughs - Celine - Artaud - Proust" course materials, 1978; 197500 (Box 51, Folder 33)
    - "Celine Express" course materials, Undated; 197501 (Box 51, Folder 34)
    - "Consuming Signs" course materials, Undated; 197502 (Box 51, Folder 35)
    - "DADA / Surrealism" syllabus and course materials, Undated; 197503 (Box 51, Folder 36)
    - "DADA, Surrealism, Situationism" course material, 2005; 197504 (Box 51, Folder 37)
    - "Death and Culture" course material, Undated; 197505 (Box 51, Folder 38)
    - "Death and Literature" syllabus, Undated; 197506 (Box 51, Folder 39)
    - "Deleuze / Guattari" syllabus, Undated; 197507 (Box 51, Folder 40)
    - "Deleuze / Proust" course materials, Undated; 197508 (Box 51, Folder 41)
    - "L'economie du roman" course materials, Undated; 197509 (Box 51, Folder 42)
    - "Ethnographic Fictions" syllabus and course materials, 1992; 197510 (Box 51, Folder 43)
    - "Ethnographic Fictions" course material, 1993; 197511 (Box 51, Folder 44)